The first night you hear him. The second night you
see him. The third night he finds you.
The Empty Man is a horror, mystery film directed by David Prior.
On the trail of a missing girl, an ex-cop comes across a secretive group
attempting to summon a terrifying supernatural entity.
James Lasombra, played by James Badge Dale.
Nora Quail, played by Marin Ireland.
Amanda Quail, played by Sasha Frolova.
Davara Walsh, played by Samantha Logan.
Greg, played by Evan Jonigkeit.
Ruthie, played by Virginia Kull.
The Empty Man is a 2020 supernatural horror film directed, written, and co-edited by David
Prior in his feature directorial debut, based on Cullen Bunn and Vanesa R.
Del Rey's graphic novel The Empty Man published by Boom!
Starring James Badge Dale and Marin Ireland, it follows an ex-cop who, upon an
investigation into a missing girl, discovers a secret cult.
Originally filmed in August 2017 as an international co-production between the United States, South Africa, and United Kingdom, the
film received poor scores at test screenings and distributor 20th Century Fox lost faith in its commercial prospects.
The final product, theatrically released in the United States on October
23, 2020, was still considered a rough edit by Prior.
Released in the midst of the COVID-19 pandemic, the film grossed $4
million worldwide against a budget of $16 million.
It received mostly negative reviews from critics and
audiences at the time of its release.
Reception improved after home video and streaming service releases, and it was
reported by some publications that The Empty Man gained a cult following.
The film explores themes of experiment,
detective, cave, missouri, investigation.
The tone is dark and mind_bending.